<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-05-14T15:13:31-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">rae.wtf</title><entry><title type="html">Version 1.2.0</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/version-120" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Version 1.2.0" /><published>2024-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/version-120</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/version-120"><![CDATA[<p>GGs on the jam, everybody!</p>

<p>Here’s a new version of the game with a buncha improvements to hopefully make the game a bit more engaging. Here’s a change-log:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Added a timer to the “rehearsal scene” where you memorize your lines! In Hard mode, you get anywhere from 10 to 30 seconds (increasing as the game progresses) to memorize the line laid out before you. In Easy mode, there’s no time limit imposed. Also, Hard mode has to be unlocked now — obtain a score of 10 or higher in Easy mode to access it! (If you crossed the threshold before, it’ll be unlocked on start-up :3)</li>
  <li>Added… <em>[pause for ironic effect]</em> …pause logic! If you go silent for too long, something will happen. In Easy mode, you’ll get some stage direction from frame right. In Hard mode, however, wait around too long and you’ll get heckled by some rude guy in the audience (+1 MISS). On that note, removed the ‘MISS’ text when you have no misses under your belt.</li>
  <li>Spruced up the look of a TON of stuff all around. New log assets, and new launcher stuff to match (and now there’s even an exit animation — hooray, polish!), new hand-drawn curtains, beefed-up animations, and new variants for tons of things all around. Even cute roses when you win! Awww.</li>
  <li>Sped up the general game flow quite a bit, allowing you to totally biff a game embarrassingly early faster than ever. Also changed some timing so that your turn starts as SOON as the spotlight turns on. Before, it’d start a little bit after, and that caused some problems from what I’ve seen.</li>
  <li>Fixed a crash where a high score variable wasn’t being updated properly. Thanx Paul!</li>
</ul>

<p>If you liked this game in the PlayJam, consider buying the game to get the latest and greatest version! If you just wanna play the original version from the jam, or wanna try a simpler version before deciding, v1.1.0 (the last version submitted in time for the jam) is still available as a free download.</p>

<p><br />
<a href="https://stuffbyrae.itch.io/first-in-line" class="button">Buy <i>First in… Line?</i> on Itch.io</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="first in... line?" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[GGs on the jam, everybody!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Version 1.1.0</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/version-110" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Version 1.1.0" /><published>2024-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/version-110</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/version-110"><![CDATA[<p>Quick update bringing a heck of a lot of new polish and features to the original build!</p>

<p>Here’s a quick change-log:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Added an Easy mode! This mode just adds onto the same pattern between rounds, in contrast to the previous standard mode (now “Hard mode”) which give you an increasingly-long completely-randomized pattern each round. Scores are saved per mode — and your best score from v1.0.0 (if you’ve got one) will still be kept as your Hard mode score. Woohoo!</li>
  <li>Speaking of stats…added a “total misses” count, as well. I meant to, but just forgot.</li>
  <li>Added some more graphics to the game over screens! Also, added some randomized costumes and extra stage members inside the gameplay sequence. Keeps it interesting! I also added a quick “How to Play” segment inside the pause menu, just in case — plus, you can now back out to the title at any time from said pause menu, even during gameplay.</li>
  <li>Your character also now makes noise when you press correct buttons! Honk, honk, honk.</li>
  <li>Bunch of minor tweaks and fixes — adding wrapping paper to launcher, new itch.io page art, bumping the FPS up from 20 to 30, adding some misc. SFX I forgot, and showing the version number on the title screen for posterity.</li>
</ul>

<p>If you’ve already downloaded the original, then sideload v1.1.0 right away for the jammiest experience possible!</p>

<p><br />
<a href="https://stuffbyrae.itch.io/first-in-line" class="button">Buy <i>First in… Line?</i> on Itch.io</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="first in... line?" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Quick update bringing a heck of a lot of new polish and features to the original build!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Playdate Update Showcase, &amp;amp;.. More!!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/playdate-update-showcase-more" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Playdate Update Showcase, &amp;amp;.. More!!" /><published>2024-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-02-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/playdate-update-showcase-more</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/playdate-update-showcase-more"><![CDATA[<h1 id="hey-folks">Hey folks!!</h1>

<p>It’s rae again! How’ve y’all been so far this year? I’ve been working pretty hard on RowBot these last few months in between college and … life, stuff; and I’ve been getting quite a bit done in the way of refactoring and getting things looking and feeling nicer to play. Personally, I think things are looking AWESOME. Like. more awesome than ever.</p>

<p>Anyway, I’m writing in because…there was a Playdate Update today! If you don’t know what that is, it’s a showcase from Panic themselves, in which they highlight some radical upcoming games for Playdate, and also some neat hardware news and stuff like that. <em>“But what does that have to do with RowBot?”</em>, you might ask? First off, ouch, and second of all, I’m happy to break the news to you…</p>

<h1 id="woah-i-was-in-there">Woah, I was in there!</h1>

<p>That’s right! Me and my game both had the immense honor of being featured in the latest Playdate Update video. If you haven’t seen the full presentation, by the way, you should go check it out! There was a ton of other cool stuff featured, and it’s a must-watch for any Playdate fans looking to stay in the loop about some rad upcoming games.</p>

<iframe class="image" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1I9mO4pYBPI?si=hpvBRCBQtyXEaVCx" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>It was super fun putting everything here together, and it’s a pretty awesome (and anxiety-inducing!) feeling seeing my game go out in front of an untold number of new faces. If you’re one of those new faces who managed to find me over here: Hello! I hope you like the game! Try out the early demo, maybe! :D</p>

<p>I wanna give my biggest heartiest thank you to everyone over at <a href="https://panic.com/">Panic</a> for giving me the incredible opportunity to be featured here. They reached out to me about it back in December, and since then I had a wonderful time working with <a href="https://voxy.space/">Voxy</a> on making the showcase video stand out among the rest, and also getting the Catalog page lookin’ ship-shape for its premiere.</p>

<p>…Oh yeah, that too!</p>

<h1 id="rowbot-rally-coming-to-catalog">RowBot Rally: Coming to Catalog<em>!!</em></h1>

<p><em>YEA LIKE HOLY SHIT RIGHT??</em></p>

<p>It’s official, it’s real, it’s <em>HAPPENING</em>. As of today, RowBot Rally is <a href="https://play.date/games/rowbot-rally">officially listed on the Playdate Catalog</a>!!!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>It’s not available for purchase just yet of course, because the game’s not…done; but you can <a href="https://play.date/games/rowbot-rally">hop on over to the game’s page</a> to give it a Wishlist! (You can also find it in the Coming Soon section of the main Catalog page, holy fuuuuuuuuuck.) By wishlisting it, you’ll get notified over email the moment it comes out for realzies. That’s pretty awesome!</p>

<p>Real talk: getting something of mine onto the Catalog has pretty much been my dream goal since I first knew about the store back in early 2023. It really felt like a place where some of the best Playdate games were allowed to shine as bright as possible, and I’m seriously so stoked that my stuff’s got the chops to be up there with ‘em. Thank you once again to Panic, and thanks to everybody reading this as well!! I don’t think my game would be anywhere near the level it is today without y’alls’ support and feedback. And bug reports — yuck.</p>

<p>I def plan to make the most of this spot in the Catalog — I’ve already put in support for on-line Leaderboards within the Time Trials mode, that way you can duke it out worldwide and compete for the top score against everybody else! This is honestly one of my favorite parts; I’m so excited to see all the competition up close and personal as soon as the game comes out later this year.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-2.png" alt="" /></p>

<h1 id="the-process">The Process™</h1>

<p>So to have a showcase spot in a Playdate Update, you need a showcase video. <em>(what a surprising fact!)</em> This means that, well…I had to make one! A minute-ish-long segment talking about who I am, what my game is, when it’s coming out and why it’s rad as hell. Usually these videos have the developer on-screen talkin’ up their game…but I hate my face, so I needed a backup plan. After a brief thought about animating the whole thing in the style of the in-game cutscenes (which would have taken me like five months, and that’s pretty unfortunate considering I only had around a month to get the whole thing done), I had an epiphany:</p>

<p>puppets;;</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-3.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Paper puppets, specifically. It was fool-proof — I could be deliberately kinda lo-fi and crafty with it, so all my mistakes look intentional, I wouldn’t have to show my face (only my voice, which was at least more easy to come to terms with), and also I figured it was a really unique way to stand out amongst everything else in the prezzie. Everyone would be all like: <em>“Did you see that idiot with the paper puppets?”</em> or whatever people say in response to things.</p>

<p>So, after one very panicked trip to the arts &amp; crafts store, I got back with some hearty cardstock, a bunch of popsicle sticks, an X-acto knife and some green posterboard. Then, it was time to get to work.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-4.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I had a real fun time working on all the assets needed for recording this project. It’s been quite a long while since I had the opportunity to get knee-deep in some proper physical material crafts like that, and it was super fun to just go nuts with an X-acto knife and experiment to see what looked good. And I didn’t injure myself once! The mark of a good quality product.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-5.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The Catalog book-throw scene was one of the earliest scenes I shot, and also probably my favorite part of the video. Ruining the movie magic: my brother helped me by throwing the book in from off-screen, since unfortunately I don’t have more than two arms (yet). The confetti was a last-minute move by me, and I think it really sold the shot — the sound effect should have been a sneeze or something though.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-6.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>It’s at this point that I wanna give major MAJOR (like, the majorest) shouts to <a href="https://voxy.space">Voxy</a>, who got me through…pretty much this entire process. He helped me clean up my super-rough script and get it fitting nicely within the timeframe we had, spruced up my voiceover to get it to acceptable levels (since I know nothing about audio editing), AND he edited the whole final cut of the video (since I also don’t know anything about video editing) — he’s responsible for all of the super tight pacing and the snazzy, appropriately-themed transitions and graphics. The final product turned out so unbelievably super good, and I really have him to thank for it turning out the way it did.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-7.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>After a hectic weekend-ish of editing and last-minute nitpicky changes (sorry!), we got the video turned in around a week before it was due (hooray for being on time!), and then it was just a long long … seemingly-forever wait until the Update video premiered on their page. And that day happens to be today! I mean, I’m writing this in advance, but I can guarantee you I’m <em>absolutely reeling</em> over it. (Update from the night before the premiere: <em>yeah i was pretty on the ball i am so reeling over it.</em>) If you wanna check out just the RowBot segment, by the way; I’ve mirrored it on my personal YouTube page here:</p>

<iframe class="image" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MNpX_rV_ItU?si=W1v19Rq6DCVwEcB8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<h1 id="okay-and-what-aboutthe-game">Okay and what about…the game?</h1>

<p>It’s been coming along really nicely, actually! So far this year, my efforts have been focused on refactoring all the existing code, and redrawing a lot of the graphics; getting everything all nice and squeaky clean both under and over the hood. I realize to some this may sound like I’m just running around in circles instead of progressing on the stuff that’s been waiting to get done for months now…and I’m not saying that <em>isn’t</em> what’s happening,</p>

<p>…that’s the end of that sentence.</p>

<p>Things have been coming along super nicely though! All the newly-freshened up stuff runs a lot better than it used to. I have some things that were previously set up <em>suuuuuuuper</em> poorly (even for my standards!) running a LOT nicer now (global functions, dynamic text strings, etc. so good), and I hope that doing this work helps me finish the remaining stuff even faster and more easily.</p>

<p>There’s also some new changes that I’ve been making that I hope will make the gameplay experience even better when the final game drops:</p>

<ul>
  <li>On-line leaderboard support for Time Trials (but you’ve already heard about this one), complete with a custom page to view all the leaderboard score (but you’ve already seen that one).</li>
  <li>Polygonizing the boat! That’s been a HUGE one. Thank you to TheMediocritist and gang for helping me set up shop with this change, as it’s been a serious game changer. It looks nicer, runs faster, and I can squash and stretch and scale and rotate it without much drawback at all. SOOOOO good.</li>
  <li>Support for three separate story save slots (so a friend or family can pop in and try out a story run without affecting your save…or you can just beat the game three times in a row. Up to you! (This was a big aspect of me deciding to start from scratch code-wise, so I could finagle the save code in here without it being even messier than it already was.))</li>
  <li>A new stats screen, so you can see global funny stats such as total time played, your favorite (most-played) and least favorite (least-played) stages, and Distance Cranked (with support for both imperial and metric)! The most important screen of all time.</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-8.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>If I can keep up the pace that I’ve been having so far, then I hope to get a new version of DEMO out sometime in mid-to-late March perhaps? School’s still happening, and I’m going off for a trip some weekend in the middle there, but things have definitely been moving along quickly, and there’s only a few more big things to touch up before this build is DEMO-ready.</p>

<p>Of course, I’m once again plugging <a href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@rae">my Mastodon page</a>, and the <a href="https://discord.com/channels/675983554655551509/1095159609620185240">Devlog thread</a> on the Playdate Squad Discord server. And, if you like a less wordy flavor… I’m now on <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/rae.wtf">Bluesky</a> as well! Usually just mirroring my Masto posts in shorter form. More frequent updates are always posted in those spots, and I’m on Discord pretty much every day so it’s the easiest way to funnel feedback my way. (I also take email, and check it regularly — there’s a link <a href="https://play.date/games/rowbot-rally">on the Catalog page</a> you can use! <em>I can’t believe I can say that now.</em>)</p>

<h1 id="one-more-thing">One More Thing…</h1>

<p>Hello!! I’m amending this post from the FUTURE…but also the past. (Like a month after I first drafted this thing up.) Today (as of writing), I just found out that RowBot Rally was also nominated for <em>Most Anticipated Game</em> in this year’s Playdate Community Awards! That’s, frankly, nuts. I believe it’s one of the only awards in the show to be entirely community-voted, so it’s especially flooring to see my game up next to one by Lucas God-Damn Pope™ in the running for things people are most excited to play this year.</p>

<p>The awards are coming around later on, so let’s see if we can snag that ultimate W…that’d be pretty cool! Regardless, though, I’m super duper excited about the nomination, and it’s really inspiring and crazy to see so many people who are this excited for my silly little boat game. From the bottom of my heart, thank YOU! 💖</p>

<h1 id="thats-it">That’s it!</h1>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2024-02-28-9.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Alright, I <em>think</em> that’s all the updates I’ve got in my back pocket for now. Back to work on the game! I’ll hopefully see y’all soon with some more things to share, but ‘till then… Sea ya later!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="rowbot rally" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey folks!!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Awards Show - Consider a Nomination!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023-awards-show-consider-a-nomination" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Awards Show - Consider a Nomination!" /><published>2023-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2023-12-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2023-awards-show-consider-a-nomination</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2023-awards-show-consider-a-nomination"><![CDATA[<h1 id="howdy">Howdy!</h1>
<p>Hey folks, rae here. It’s December! (my <em>godddddd!</em>)</p>

<p>So, if you’ve been in the Playdate-verse for a while, you know that last year TYM hosted a community awards ceremony, handing badges and bragging rights to some of the primo games released throughout 2022 in Playdate history. This year, they’re doing it again! And unlike last year…i’m here. :3</p>

<p>I’ve got a…few things in the pipeline lately, but my big project is clearly RowBot. So, I’m officially putting the call out there for folks that are hyped about the game: make your voice heard, and <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfqM3AZnv3F8Vi-_jT_sUtretB10yW3RRo4LT1Inw0DTYf3ag/viewform?usp=sf_link">nominate RowBot Rally for Most Anticipated Game</a> at this year’s awards show!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2023-12-04-1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>It’d mean a lot to me if you did. This year has been amazing for me, thanks in absolutely no small part to Playdate, this community, and everything people have put out and been working on through this year and beyond. It’s been so fun seeing both others working on insane games and apps, and people being excited for the stuff I’m making as well (like, what???). Whether you wanna nominate my game or not, get in there and vote for your favorites! (trust me, there’s a <em>bunch</em> of categories.)</p>

<h1 id="anything-else">Anything else?</h1>

<p>Well, on the RowBot side of things, at least…not much LOL! This whole fall has been very hectic, with classes and lots of pet projects taking up a hefty chunk of time that would have been otherwise available to me. I’ve got this whole of December off, and I wanna focus that time into finishing up and releasing a smaller game of mine, and then cracking back down on RowBot after that’s squared away.</p>

<p>There has been one big breakthrough recently…and that’s Procreate Dreams. As you may or may not know, the current cutscenes in the DEMO version of the game were animated using Procreate. Procreate is an amazing drawing and painting tool for iPads! Procreate is also a really not-great animation tool. It’s serviceable, it works, but there’s no support for motion tweens, in-depth editing or audio of any kind, and it’s kinda grafted onto the existing layer system which makes handling a longer-form project like this really…messy. But!! Dreams seems like it has INCREDIBLE potential for the future of these animated cutscenes, to the point where I may try my hand at redoing the existing ones as well. (Cue the eye roll from the people who’ve already seen like three different versions of that first cutscene :woozy_face:)</p>

<p>There’s definitely a…steep learning curve to the app. Even as a self-considered Procreate expert (not a euphemism), there’s a lot of…weird stuff? Like, why is the onion skin hiding in the timecode bar. Why. BUT I hope to have some more RowBot updates coming around Soon™™™™™ enough!! I definitely can’t really promise anything in the near-term, which SUCKS because I hate leaving projects on the back-burner, but life’s just been really swiping my attention away from most-any gamedev lately. You know how it is.</p>

<p>Anyway! That’s the gist of it! Why not <a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfqM3AZnv3F8Vi-_jT_sUtretB10yW3RRo4LT1Inw0DTYf3ag/viewform?usp=sf_link">get out there and gimme a nommy</a> if you’re feeling so inclined, but otherwise… Sea ya later!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="rowbot rally" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Howdy! Hey folks, rae here. It’s December! (my godddddd!)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Demo Update, and Recent Happenings!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/demo-update-and-recent-happenings" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Demo Update, and Recent Happenings!" /><published>2023-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-10-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/demo-update-and-recent-happenings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/demo-update-and-recent-happenings"><![CDATA[<h1 id="howdy">Howdy!</h1>

<p>It’s rae again! Happy Monday! Before I get into the meat of this post, I just wanna talk about how much I appreciate all of the support that this game’s been getting, both in general and especially since the launch of the demo! I’ve gotten so much good feedback, bug reports, and all that jazz, and it’s frankly all been really exciting to experience. To think that people are actually as pumped to see my game come to fruition as I am to make it is pretty radical. Thank you all so much!!</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2023-10-10-1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Anyway, I’m here because I’ve got a couple of pieces of news to share; a new update as well as some recent developments from the past month or so! Let’s start with the thing that affects you right now…</p>

<h1 id="new-demo-update">New Demo Update!</h1>

<p>Yup, as of TODAY there’s a new version of the demo build available to download! While there’s no new <em>content</em> available here (naturally), there’s a whole slew of bug fixes and updates and little tweaks to hopefully make your experience that much better, both right now as well as after the game comes out. What kind of stuff, you ask? Well, here’s a handy change log!</p>

<h2 id="demo-v020">Demo v0.2.0</h2>

<h3 id="added">Added</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Accessibility Settings! — New gameplay tweaks and toggle-able options to hopefully make this game more playable by everybody. These can be found in Options &gt; Accessibility.
    <ul>
      <li>D-pad Controls — Play the game using controls adapted for buttons only, instead of the crank. Pressing d-pad up will increase your rowing power, and holding d-pad Down will decrease it.</li>
      <li>Auto-Skip — This option skips any non-essential parts of the game, such as the tutorial, any cutscenes, and later on, the credits.</li>
      <li>Row Sensitivity — This adjusts how hard you need to row to match pace with, or overtake, your RowBot. This affects the standard crank controls, as well as the d-pad controls, if enabled.</li>
      <li>Power Flip — A simple cosmetic change that flips the Power Meter, if you prefer it that way. This has no effect if Pro UI is enabled.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="changed">Changed</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Options Rebuild! — The Options menu has been rebuilt from the ground up. This makes it waaay more cromulent both under and over the hood, and also suits the new Accessibility menu quite well.</li>
  <li>Pro UI Move — The “Pro UI” toggle has been moved into the Accessibility sub-menu of the Options. You can still change it quickly mid-race, through the slide menu!</li>
  <li>On-again, Off-again — There’s now some new better-looking graphics for on/off toggles in the Options. Instead of just text, now there’s a neat animated little graphic. Hooray!</li>
  <li>Race Tweak — Adjusted the default rowing speeds just a touch, in order to suit the new Accessibility options like the Row Sensitivity.</li>
  <li>Dizzied Out — Removed a slightly-secret thing where steering really fast would make the reaction images go dizzy. This was causing some unintended problems (see Fixed no. 1), though I’d like to re-add this a bit later on if I can figure out a better way to pull it off.</li>
  <li>Title Tweaks — Adjusted how the “Start!” screen works a tad. Now, hitting A before the logo fully finishes animating in won’t cause a harsh jump up. Polish, polish, polish!</li>
  <li>Crash, Dummy! — Crashing sounds now play at a slightly-variable rate, instead of the same one all the time.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="fixed">Fixed</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Reactions React — The reaction images in the Power Meter now properly react when crashing into a wall.</li>
  <li>Collision Course — Retooled the collision system during a race, which should hopefully quell some rare-ish issues where sometimes you’d be sent into a wall, instead of out of it. Thanks to scratchminer and Toad for helping me out with this, as always. Collisions suuuck, and I vow never to collide with anything again.</li>
  <li>The Most Important White Chunk In The World — The little description blockquote-block thing in the race intro now appears as it’s supposed to. I was just forgetting to set the color to white properly, my bad.</li>
  <li>Point and Click — The guiding arrows in the Tutorial will now disappear when you crash for the first time. Before, the arrows would cover up the A button prompt on the guide UI, which is what we in the industry call a Big Whoopsie™.</li>
  <li>Wake for it… — Fixed a small visual bug which was preventing the “full left-turn” wake image from appearing properly. It was just some totally stupid elseif troubles, and a thing was triggering before another thing causing the thing that I wanted to happen to not happen. GREAT STUFF ALL AROUND! Thanks Voxy for helping me snipe that one.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="changed-not-that-youd-know">Changed, not that you’d know…</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Save Indicator! — A little indicator appears in the top-left corner any time the game’s writing data to disk. This has no bearing in the demo, where there’s not really any data to save. Before, I was editing saves during the middle of gameplay, and only committing them to disk when the user closed the game. This wasn’t really effective in the event of, say, a crash, where the game wouldn’t have a chance to save while bailing out. Oops, lost progress! That should hopefully be quelled now.</li>
  <li>Delete, Deleted — The “Reset Data” setting in the Options menu has been removed. Doesn’t matter in the demo for obvious reasons, but I realized that this button was probably a little redundant/confusing in the end. In the future, if you’d like to clear all data in the final game, you can do so from Playdate’s system Settings. You can also start a new game without clearing all of your other progress such as best times or unlocks.</li>
  <li>Splash Text — The title screen now has splash texts at the top, after your first time logging in. Well, not in the demo — I dunno whether it’s your first time playing or your hundredth. (Why would you play one demo that much?!) So, this is a final-game-only thing, at least for now…but they’ll be arguably funny, I promise.</li>
</ul>

<p>That all being said…if you find a bug, or you have a piece of feedback, please let me know! There are email links on the main page of this game, but you can also contact me over Mastodon or my Discord, if you’ve got it. Anyway, with the change log out of the way, let’s see what else has been going on in the world of RowBot!</p>

<h1 id="igda-twin-cities">IGDA Twin Cities!</h1>

<p>Towards the end of September, the game demo was featured in the IGDA Twin Cities Playtest stream! I’d like to thank Mark LaCroix, and everybody at <a href="https://noblerobot.com/">Noble Robot</a> and the <a href="https://igdatc.org/">IGDA Twin Cities chapter</a> for letting me join, it was an absolute blast seeing people try my game live, the whole way through, for the first time. If you wanna check out the stream, there’s a replay here on YouTube (originally aired September 20th, 2023):</p>

<iframe class="image" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_XBWTnATILI?si=wnfViDx-PSLjJNs4&amp;start=3046" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>One thing about the playtesters’ experiences that really surprised me…this game was HARD. Like, <em>pretty dang hard</em>. I learned that I’ve succumbed to a type of “developer bias” — I’ve (of course) been with my game, hand in hand, over the entire course of its development. So, since I know all the bits and bobs, I think it’s pretty easy to control. I’ve gotten used to it! The folks who have never tried or even seen this game before, respectfully…were crashin’ into walls a LOT more than I’d expected hahaha. It definitely makes me think I’ll need to tweak some stuff and see if i can make the control scheme any easier to get a crank on, since the difficulty level from the perspective of a new player really blew me away frankly.</p>

<p>The good news, is that (at least from what they were saying), it seems like a <em>good</em> kind of hard. Like, that specific point of difficulty where you feel like it’s not the fault of the game for controlling poorly but instead the fault of you for not having a good enough grip on the controls — I think in the industry, this is called ‘The Foddy Zone’. I hope I can play into that kind of difficulty for the later parts of the game, but for the first course it definitely might be way too much. IT’S A LEARNING EXPERIENCE FOR THE AGES!!</p>

<h1 id="playdate-community-direct">Playdate Community Direct!</h1>

<p>Oh yeah, last week(!) my game was also featured in <a href="https://youtube.com/@tinyyellowmachine">Tiny Yellow Machine</a>’s Playdate Community Direct!! The trailer featured is up on this game’s main page, but I highly encourage you to check out the full direct replay on YouTube, featuring a TON of really really rad Playdate games in-development! (originally aired October 5th, 2023):</p>

<iframe class="image" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xoV-zXigJtg?si=0z2JYP4kUgrPQOWY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>Thank you to Gant for hosting this entire thing! Myself and many others are very happy to come together and see what the Playdate community is up to lately. I’d also like to thank <a href="https://toadleyundercontrol.itch.io/">Toad</a> for helping me out with editing together the trailer! I was really toeing the deadline and frankly dreading having to fire open the video editing software, so you really saved my tail here. Also, shoutouts to everybody in the direct’s live chat who almost-immediately started hyping my game up as soon as it came on screen!! That was REALLY awesome to see, and it frankly put quite into perspective the amount of excitement that my silly little boat game is stirring up.</p>

<h1 id="thats-all-for-now">That’s all for now!</h1>

<p>Okay, back to work for me! I’ve been busy with a LOT of other stuff lately (quite a few things of mine were shown off in that very same community Direct, actually!), so I dunno exactly when I’ll be back with more RowBot news to share. Make sure to keep tabs on my <a href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@rae">Mastodon</a> page, as well as <a href="https://discord.com/channels/675983554655551509/1095159609620185240">the devlog thread in the Playdate Squad Discord server</a> for more frequent (if small and oft-off-topic) updates on the game if you’re interested! Until next time, though: Sea ya later!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="rowbot rally" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Howdy!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Try the Demo - Out Today!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/try-the-demo-out-today" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Try the Demo - Out Today!" /><published>2023-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2023-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/try-the-demo-out-today</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/try-the-demo-out-today"><![CDATA[<h1 id="howdy">Howdy!</h1>

<p>My name’s rae (in case you missed it), and I’ve been working on a game for Playdate called RowBot Rally (in case you missed <em>that</em>)! Play as a bunny teaming up with a defective ‘RowBot’ to take down an evil corporation who’s monopolized the entire competitive rowing circuit - and hopefully, have some fun while doing it! I started working on this game in April, and since then there’s been lots of ups and downs (and sideways?!), but today I’ve finally got my first piece of Big News™ to share…</p>

<h1 id="the-demos-out">The demo’s out!</h1>

<p>That’s right! Starting TODAY…you can try out a curated sampling of the first chunk of the game, for the low low price of…free! You can get through it pretty quick, but such is the nature of a demo. The demo includes the tutorial level (so you can get the hang of the controls), the first stage of the game, as well as the first two fully-animated cutscenes! Marvel and witness the glorious 1-bit goodness.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2023-08-31-1.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>Of course, this demo is just a small piece of the full game, which I plan to launch later on, so stay tuned for that!</p>

<h1 id="heads-up">Heads up…</h1>

<p>Since this demo’s coming out well before the final game, it should be noted that pretty much anything in this game’s subject to change in the time between now and then - so there might be some things that’ll get improved or changed, bugs that’ll be fixed, etc etc. That being said: if you notice any bugs, feel free to contact me with the support link on the main page! There’s also a dedicated contact for feedback, if you have any of that as well - if there’s something you expected to be some other way, or something you think just looks Weird, I wanna hear about it!</p>

<p>Also, do note that in this demo, none of your data will be saved - so that’s story progress, best times, etc. - this is partially a limitation of the bundle IDs (since the demo’s is different from the final game), and partly because I don’t really think it’s enough of the story to warrant keeping track of the player’s progress. If you manage to snag a new personal record, though, do show me! I’d love to see it.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2023-08-31-2.gif" alt="" /></p>

<p>One last thing to note: this demo doesn’t run quiiiiite at full-speed just yet when using the Mirror app. On a device, you should clock a consistent 30fps (if you don’t, let me know!!), but if you’re on Mirror, it’ll dip to somewhere around 29-28fps in-game. I plan to optimize with Mirror in mind for the full release, once I have all of the race mechanics built - it’s an important step towards accessibility and just plain comfort, so I’d really like for my game to function with as well as it does without. If you wanna clock your FPS speed right now, here’s a <em>Row Tip™</em>: hold B and press A on the title screen to toggle a counter in the corner. Neat!</p>

<h1 id="what-about-the-full-game">What about the full game?</h1>

<p>Well, this game’s proving tougher to get out the door than I expected (fun fact: this demo is coming out on my initial projected release date for the <em>entire game!</em> How’s that for an underestimation?) - that, combined with some other stuff I’m busy hammering out during this last chunk of the year, means I don’t have any specific release date in mind yet. If I can manage it, I’d liiike to gun for a release somewhere in the first half of 2024? It could release earlier – could release later! I genuinely do not know, and my past track record is advising me to not make a guess.</p>

<p><img src="/blog/images/2023-08-31-3.png" alt="" /></p>

<p>If you wanna keep track on updates as I have ‘em, you can <a href="https://mastodon.gamedev.place/@rae">follow me on Mastodon</a>! There, I post the cool stuff - large strides I’ve taken with the code, or the art, some fun tip I found and promptly implemented, or whatever-else. If you wanna get into the real nitty-gritty, mostly-off-topic, the TRUE development experience; then you can <a href="https://discord.com/channels/675983554655551509/1095159609620185240">follow the dev-log currently in-progress</a> in the Playdate Squad Discord! If neither of those speak to you and you only want the REALLY big stuff - well I’ll post those right here on the itch.io page (you are here)! These kindsa posts should only really happen when there’s a new public release of the game, or somethin’ really important just happened.</p>

<h1 id="readysetrow">Ready…set…ROW!</h1>

<p>Alright, that’s all I’ve got to say! Get out there and try out that demo, and let me know what you think! I wanna thank everyone who’s been rooting for me throughout this whole experience so far - this is the first proper game that I’ve made, and it’s been super inspiring to see people I see as role models goin’ “oh yeah this game’s swag as fuck” and offering real good advice…but I’ll save the real sappiness for the postmortem.</p>

<p>Anyway, go enjoy that demo, and until next time: Sea ya later!</p>

<p><br />
<a href="https://rae.wtf/rowbot-rally/DEMO.zip" class="button">Download RowBot Rally DEMO</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="rowbot rally" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Howdy!]]></summary></entry></feed>